Register of the Alfred M. Lilienthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1936-1994 (Boxes 9-30, 152-153)
  - Seifeddine, Sami, 1981 (Box-folder 28: 16)
  - Seliger, Ralph G., 1975 (Box-folder 28: 17)
  - Shadid, George, 1968 (Box-folder 28: 18)
  - Shadyac, Richard C., See also Arab-American Dialogue Committee, 1969-1983. (Box-folder 28: 19)
  - Shahak, Israel, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 28: 20)
  - Sharaf, Abdul Hamid, 1980 (Box-folder 28: 21)
  - Sharp, Eliot H., 1985 (Box-folder 28: 22)
  - Sheehan, Edward R. F., 1973 (Box-folder 28: 23)
  - Shereshevsky, Simon, 1965 (Box-folder 28: 24)
  - Sherif, Mahmoud I. el-, 1978 (Box-folder 28: 25)
  - Sherif, Mehmet and Betty Anne, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 28: 26)
  - Shibley, George E., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 28: 27)
  - Shoman, Abdulrahman, 1979 (Box-folder 28: 28)
  - Shukrallah, Ibrahim, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 28: 29)
  - Shultz, George P., 1984-1988 (Box-folder 28: 30)
  - Shumway, Norman D., 1979-1984 (Box-folder 28: 31)
  - Siddique, Kaubab, 1982 (Box-folder 28: 32)
  - Siegel, Stanley, 1978 (Box-folder 28: 33)
  - Sign, 1964 (Box-folder 28: 34)
  - Silver, Abba Hillel, n.d. (Box-folder 28: 35)
  - Sima'an, Ne'meh J., 1974-1980 (Box-folder 28: 36)
  - Simon and Schuster, 1971 (Box-folder 28: 37)
  - Simon Wiesenthal Center, n.d. (Box-folder 28: 38)
  - Simpson, Dwight James, 1980 (Box-folder 28: 39)
  - Sirhan, Mary, 1969 (Box-folder 28: 40)
  - Skeini, Mutih, 1981 (Box-folder 28: 41)
  - Smith, Elizabeth, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 28: 42)
  - Smith, H. Alexander, 1949 (Box-folder 28: 43)
  - Smith, Lawrence H., 1949 (Box-folder 28: 44)
  - Smith, Richard, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 28: 45)
  - Smith, Richard K., 1978-1981 (Box-folder 28: 46)
  - Societe tunisienne de banque, 1965 (Box-folder 28: 47)
  - Solarz, Stephen J., 1981-1984 (Box-folder 28: 48)
  - Somalia. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1970 (Box-folder 28: 49)
  - Sorensen, Thomas C., 1961 (Box-folder 28: 50)
  - Souder, M. Attie, 1965 (Box-folder 28: 51)
  - Southern State College, 1967 (Box-folder 28: 52)
  - Southern Yemen. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1968 (Box-folder 28: 53)
  - Southport Congressional Church, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 28: 54)
  - Soviet Union. Embassy (United States), 1983 (Box-folder 28: 55)
  - Sparkman, John, 1975 (Box-folder 28: 56)
  - Spears, Edward L., 1955 (Box-folder 28: 57)
  - Spehl, Helmut, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 28: 58)
  - St. George Orthodox Church (Cleveland), 1976 (Box-folder 28: 59)
  - St. Martin's Press, 1964 (Box-folder 28: 60)
  - St. Nicholas Syrian Orthodox Cathedral of Brooklyn, 1970 (Box-folder 28: 61)
  - St. Thomas Chamber of Commerce, 1979 (Box-folder 28: 62)
  - Standard Oil, 1960-1978 (Box-folder 28: 63)
  - Stassen, Harold E., 1948-1951 (Box-folder 28: 64)
  - Stendahl, Kirster, 1985 (Box-folder 28: 65)
  - Stephen, Fares, 1982 (Box-folder 28: 66)
  - Sterling, Jan, 1977 (Box-folder 28: 67)
  - Stetson University, 1981 (Box-folder 28: 68)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1964 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Stinespring, William F., 1966-1984 (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - Stoddard, George, 1960 (Box-folder 29: 3)
  - Stone, Hyman, 1959 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Stone, I. F., 1979 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - Stone, Oliver, 1992 (Box-folder 152: 47)
  - Strauss, J., 1975 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1964-1967 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Suchman, Rae, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - Sudan. Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1967 (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Sudan. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1967 (Box-folder 29: 10)
  - Suez Canal Authority, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 29: 11)
  - Suja, Stanislav, 1985 (Box-folder 29: 12)
  - Susskind, David, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 29: 13)
  - Sussman, Leonard R., n.d. (Box-folder 29: 14)
  - Sylvester, Robert, 1956 (Box-folder 29: 15)
  - Syria. Embassy (United States), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 29: 16)
  - Syria. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 29: 17)
  - Syria. Presidential Palace, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 29: 18)
  - Syrian Antiochian Orthodox Archdiocese, 1969 (Box-folder 29: 19)
  - Talcott, Burt L., 1969 (Box-folder 29: 20)
  - Tamari, Ludwig W. and Joseph
    - 1960-1969 (Box-folder 29: 21)
    - 1970-1982 (Box-folder 29: 22)
  - Tariki, Abdullah H., 1963-1980 (Box-folder 29: 23)
  - Tell, Wasfie el-, 1962 (Box-folder 29: 24)
  - Terry, Janice J., 1986 (Box-folder 29: 25)
  - Theberge, James D., 1960 (Box-folder 29: 26)
  - Thimmesch, Nick, 1978 (Box-folder 29: 27)
  - Thomas, Bruce A., 1961-1969 (Box-folder 29: 28)
  - Thomas, Lowell, 1981 (Box-folder 29: 29)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 29: 30)
  - Thompson, Cliff F., 1955 (Box-folder 29: 31)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1950 (Box-folder 29: 32)
  - Thorpe, Merle, Jr., 1979-1981 (Box-folder 29: 33)
  - Thurmond, Strom, 1970 (Box-folder 29: 34)
  - Tikkun (Michael Lerner), 1987 (Box-folder 152: 48)
  - Time, 1962-1985 (Box-folder 29: 35)
  - Tonkon, I. Edward, 1957 (Box-folder 29: 36)
  - Toukan, Jamal, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 29: 37)
  - Toynbee, Arnold, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 29: 38)
  - Trager, Frank N., 1981 (Box-folder 29: 39)
  - Trans World Airlines, 1960 (Box-folder 29: 40)
  - Travis, Maury M., 1981-1983 (Box-folder 29: 41)
  - Tri-Lateral Commission, 1979 (Box-folder 29: 42)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1952-1969 (Box-folder 29: 43)
  - Tueni, Ghassan, 1973 (Box-folder 29: 44)
  - Tunisia. Embassy (Great Britain), 1965 (Box-folder 29: 45)
  - Tunisia. Embassy (United States), 1980-1984 (Box-folder 29: 46)
  - Tunisia. Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 47)
  - Tunisia. Ministry of Information, 1965 (Box-folder 29: 48)
  - Tunisia. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1981 (Box-folder 29: 49)
  - Tunisia. Secretariat of State, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 29: 50)
  - Tuquan, Fawwaz A., 1968 (Box-folder 29: 51)
  - Turner, Edward H., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 29: 52)
  - Twitchell, Karl S., 1956 (Box-folder 29: 53)
  - Tyndale, Harry (Box-folder 29: 54)
  - U.S. Labor Party, 1979 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Ulman, William A., 1979 (Box-folder 30: 2)
  - Union des progressistes juifs de Belgique, 1984 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - United American-Arab Congress, 1970 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - United Arab Emirates. Chief of Staff, 1974 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - United Arab Emirates. Council of Ministers, 1979 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - United Arab Emirates. Embassy (United States), 1977-1981 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - United Arab Emirates. Ministry of Information, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - United Arab Emirates. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - United Church Board for World Ministries, 1968 (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - United Church of Canada, 1979 (Box-folder 30: 11)
  - United Nations Organization, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - United Palestinian Appeal, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 13)
  - United States Arab-Asian Institute, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 30: 14)
  - United States. Congress. Senate. Foreign Relations Committee, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 30: 15)
  - United States. Department of Energy, 1978 (Box-folder 30: 16)
  - United States. Department of State, 1954-1981 (Box-folder 30: 17)
  - United States. Embassy (Iraq), 1965 (Box-folder 30: 18)
  - United States. Embassy (Syria), 1976 (Box-folder 30: 19)
  - United States. Postmaster General, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 30: 20)
  - United States. Strategic Institute, 1979 (Box-folder 30: 21)
  - University Christian Movement, 1968 (Box-folder 30: 22)
  - University of Cairo, 1970 (Box-folder 30: 23)
  - Uris, Leon, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 24)
  - US Farmers Association, 1978 (Box-folder 30: 25)
  - Van Renssalaer Thayer, Mary, 1971 (Box-folder 30: 26)
  - Vance, Cyrus R., 1983 (Box-folder 30: 27)
  - Vatican, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 30: 28)
  - Vetter, Ruthe, 1965 (Box-folder 30: 29)
  - Vidal, Gore, 1993 (Box-folder 153: 19)
  - Vital Speeches, 1970 (Box-folder 30: 30)
  - Von Foeppel, John, 1978 (Box-folder 30: 31)
  - Von Roijens, Robert D., 1969 (Box-folder 30: 32)
  - Waldheim, Kurt, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 30: 33)
  - Walker, Harry, 1975 (Box-folder 30: 34)
  - Wallace, Mike, 1978 (Box-folder 30: 35)
  - Wallen, Norman, 1985 (Box-folder 30: 36)
  - Walters, Barbara, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 30: 37)
  - Walters, Dennis, 1981 (Box-folder 30: 38)
  - Walz, L. Humphrey, 1958-1981 (Box-folder 30: 39)
  - Wandel, Fridtjof, 1969 (Box-folder 30: 40)
  - Watkins, David, 1977 (Box-folder 30: 41)
  - Weber, William D., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 30: 42)
  - Wedemeyer, A. C., 1979 (Box-folder 30: 43)
  - Weigle, Richard D., 1971 (Box-folder 30: 44)
  - Weinberger, Caspar W., 1982-1984 (Box-folder 30: 45)
  - Wells, Marion W., 1983 (Box-folder 30: 46)
  - Western Guard Party (Canada), 1979 (Box-folder 30: 47)
  - Westmoreland, W. C. (Box-folder 30: 48)
  - Wetherhill, Samuel P., 1959 (Box-folder 30: 49)
  - Wheeler, R. A., n.d. (Box-folder 30: 50)
  - White, W. L., 1949 (Box-folder 30: 51)
  - Wicker, Tom, 1985 (Box-folder 30: 52)
  - Williams, Bob, 1976 (Box-folder 30: 53)
  - Willkie, Wendell L., 1943 (Box-folder 30: 54)
  - WKPA, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 55)
  - Women's National Republican Club, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 30: 56)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center, 1978 (Box-folder 30: 57)
  - Woolfson, Marion, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 30: 58)
  - World Muslim Congress, 1968 (Box-folder 30: 59)
  - World Without War Council, 1973 (Box-folder 30: 60)
  - Wouk, Herman, 1949 (Box-folder 30: 61)
  - Youman, Roger J., 1979 (Box-folder 30: 62)
  - Younes, Mahmoud. See Suez Canal Authority
  - Young, Andrew, 1977 (Box-folder 30: 63)
  - Young Arab Organization, UCLA, 1961 (Box-folder 30: 64)
  - Younis, Adele L., 1966 (Box-folder 30: 65)
  - Yugoslavia. Permanent Mission to the United Nations, 1978 (Box-folder 30: 66)
  - Zablocki, Clement J., 1981 (Box-folder 30: 67)
  - Zahid, Yussif, 1965 (Box-folder 30: 68)
  - Zakaib, George N., 1981 (Box-folder 30: 69)
  - Zanopoulo, George, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 30: 70)
  - Zayyad, Fuad S. Abu, 1974 (Box-folder 30: 71)
  - Zeidane, Georges Z., 1967-1969 (Box-folder 30: 72)
  - Ziegler, Ronald L., 1973 (Box-folder 30: 73)
  - Zind, Frederic F., 1969 (Box-folder 30: 74)
  - Zschau, Ed, 1984 (Box-folder 30: 75)
  - Zu'bi, Mohammed Sharif, 1981 (Box-folder 30: 76)
  - Zunes, Helen, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 30: 77)
  - Zurayk, Costi, See also Plimpton, Calvin H., 1966. (Box-folder 30: 78)
  - Zwan, A. G., 1967-1969 (Box-folder 30: 79)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1995 (Boxes 31-68, 152-153)
  Articles, book drafts, essays, letters to the editor, press releases, radio broadcasts, speeches, and statements, arranged chronologically.
  See also: SUBJECT FILE, Arab boycott, NAAA Conference; Bahrain; Israel, Letter-bomb campaign; Media, Writings of AML; MIDDLE EAST PERSPECTIVE, Writings of AML.
  - "Lecture/Radio/TV schedule" compiled by AML, listing lectures and media appearances of AML, from to the present, 1947 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Fragments and short unpublished pieces (Box-folder 31: 2-4)
  - Notes and quotes
    - Lectures (Box-folder 31: 5-8)
    - Miscellaneous (Boxes 31-32)
  - "Agony and Ecstasy," n.d. Writings and research material for a projected book (still being contemplated). See also TRIPS TO THE MIDDLE EAST, 1958, 1976, and 1978
    - 1957-1976 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - 1959-1978 (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - 1964-1975 (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - 1966-1969 (Box-folder 33: 4)
    - (personal - for autobiography), 1966-1978 (Box-folder 33: 5)
    - (personal - for autobiography), 1970-1975 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - (White House), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - 1971-1977 (Box-folder 34: 2)
    - 1972-1976 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - 1973-1977 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    - 1973-1981 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - (Ma'alot), 1974 (Box-folder 34: 6)
    - (Nixon, Ford, Sadat), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 34: 7)
    - 1974-1977 (Box-folder 34: 8)
    - 1974-1982 (Box-folder 34: 9)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 34: 10)
    - (Media), 1977 (Box-folder 34: 11)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 34: 12)
  - "The Balfour Declaration," Typescript radio broadcast, n.d. (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - "Bomb Me not! Still What Price Israel?" n.d. Typescript of an unpublished book (precursor of The Zionist Connection) (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - "A Federated Europe, the Answer to the German Dilemma," Typescript (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - "How Is One a Jew?" Typescript. Includes research notes on the subject "religion versus nationalism", n.d. (Box-folder 35: 4)
  - "A Mini-Study of the Volcanic Middle East," Typescript, n.d. (Box-folder 35: 5)
  - "O My People: The Only Road toward Middle East Peace," Typescript, n.d. (Box-folder 35: 6)
  - "Semite and Anti-Semite: A Cover-Up for Israelism?" Typescript. Includes several drafts that were originally meant for a book on the same subject (Box-folder 35: 7)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Typescript, n.d. (Box-folder 35: 8)
  - Letter to the editor, The Judge, (date written). Carbon copy, 2 April 1938 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Open letter to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Mimeographed copy, 5 May 1938. (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - "Economic Warfare in Portugal: The Battle for Wolfram," Study for the Department of State, Division of Defense Materials. Carbon copy, 1943? (Box-folder 36: 3)
  - Statement on the United Nations charter before the Foreign Relations Committee, Mimeographed copy, 13 July 1945. (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Speech, Rotary Club of Brooklyn, New York, Mimeographed copy, 12 September 1945. (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times?, (date written). Carbon copy, 2 October 1945 (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Comments, special radio broadcast commemorating the first anniversary of the San Francisco Conference, with members of the One World Club discussing the subject "Food or Famine in One World," Mutual Broadcasting System, St. John's Church, Washington, D.C. Mimeographed copy, 1946. (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, (date written). Carbon copy, 9 January 1946 (Box-folder 36: 8)
  - Introduction of Hon. Henry C. Usbourne, member of Parliament, before the Public Relations Force, Hotel Lafayette, Washington, D.C., Carbon copy, 29 September 1947. (Box-folder 36: 9)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, (date written). Carbon copy, 6 November 1947 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Carbon copy, 16 January 1948 (Box-folder 36: 11)
  - "Palestine Policy," Washington Post, Printed copy, 10 March 1948. (Box-folder 36: 12)
  - "Dear Mom" letter used in radio broadcast after the Republican Convention, Carbon copy, c. June 1948. (Box-folder 36: 13)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald Tribune, (date written). Carbon copy, 16 August 1948 (Box-folder 36: 14)
  - "Man Can Split Atom but not 2 Lilienthals," Washington Post, Printed copy, 17 October 1948. (Box-folder 36: 15)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Evening Star, (date written). Carbon copy, 29 October 1948 (Box-folder 36: 16)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Carbon copy, 1 November 1948 (Box-folder 36: 17)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald Tribune, Printed copy, 14 November 1948. (Box-folder 36: 18)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Handwritten draft, c. 1949. (Box-folder 36: 19)
  - "A Mecca for Communists," Typescript, 1949. (Box-folder 36: 20)
  - "Israel's Flag Is not Mine," Reader's Digest, September 1949. See also Letter to the editor, Baltimore Sun?, c. September-October 1949
    - Printed copy (Box-folder 36: 21)
    - Carbon copy drafts. Includes revisions approved by Elmer Berger (Box-folder 36: 22)
    - Readers' letters (Box-folder 36: 23-24)
  - Letter to the editor, Baltimore Sun?, Printed copy, c. September-October 1949. (Box-folder 36: 25)
  - "Dual Loyalty: The Jerusalem Case," Human Events, Printed copy, 18 January 1950. (Box-folder 36: 26)
  - "The State of Israel and the State of the Jew," 3 March 1950. Speech, Temple Israel Meeting, New York City. Printed copy, Vital Speeches, 15 April 1950 (Box-folder 36: 27)
  - Remarks, round table: The American Jew Looks at Israel, Montgomery County Jewish Community, Silver Spring, Maryland, Correspondence with Marcus Cohn and clippings, 14 March 1950. (Box-folder 36: 28)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, (date written). Typescript and printed copy, 16 May 1950 (Box-folder 36: 29)
  - "Storm Clouds over the Middle East," Human Events, Printed copy, 2 August 1950. (Box-folder 36: 30)
  - Account of trip to Portugal, Carbon copy, 1950. (Box-folder 36: 31)
  - Press release calling for immediate admission of Portugal into the United Nations, Carbon copy, 15 September 1950. (Box-folder 36: 32)
  - "Which Way to World Government?," Headline Series, Foreign Policy Association, Printed copy, September-October 1950. (Box-folder 36: 33)
  - "The Next President," 1951-1952. Series of four political commentaries, intended for a program on YMCA Radio but also sent to the New York Herald Tribune (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Printed copy, 10 January 1951. (Box-folder 152: 49)
  - "Analysis of News for the Week Ending on 8 April 1951," The Light from Capitol Hill radio program. Typescript and carbon copy. Includes correspondence with Helen Moodie, Atlantic Union (Box-folder 37: 2)
  - "Dear Whitey" letter, 30 December 1951. Carbon copy. Includes correspondence with Whitelaw Reid ( New York Herald Tribune) (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - "The Challenge of the Arab Refugees," 1952. Typescript and carbon copy. Includes letter to the editor of Readers' Forum, regarding Arab refugees in Gaza (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - "Revolt along the Nile," Mercury, Printed copy, February 1952. (Box-folder 37: 5)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Printed copy, 4 February 1952. (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - "Is there a Jewish Vote?" Human Events, Printed copy, 26 March 1952. (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Press release asking Dwight D. Eisenhower and Robert A. Taft to state Middle East plans, Mimeographed copy and clipping, 1 July 1952. (Box-folder 37: 8)
  - "The Explosive Middle East," The American Legion Magazine, Printed copy, September 1952. (Box-folder 37: 9)
  - Press release urging immediate joint action on the part of presidential candidates to save the Middle East, Mimeographed copy, 17 October 1952. (Box-folder 37: 10)
  - What Price Israel?, 1953
    - Comments (Box-folder 37: 11)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 37: 12-18)
    - Mailing lists (Box-folder 37: 19)
    - Orders (Box-folder 37: 20-21)
    - Publicity material (Box-folder 37: 22)
    - Reviews (Box-folder 37: 23)
    - Thank you notes and acknowledgements (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - Writings of AML regarding the Japanese translation. Includes correspondence (Box-folder 38: 2)
  - "The Real Meaning of the Prague Trials," Typescript outline, January 1953. (Box-folder 38: 3)
  - Two radio broadcasts for NBC, on the arrival of Secretary John F. Dulles in Cairo, Egypt. Typescript, c. May 1-6 1953 (Box-folder 38: 4)
  - Interview of Gamal Abdel Nasser, (radio broadcast cancelled by NBC). Typescript and clipping, 7 May 1953 (Box-folder 38: 5)
  - Statement, (two different versions). Carbon copies, 10 May 1953 (Box-folder 38: 6)
  - Press release, demanding a "clean break" with pressure groups in order to better relations with Middle East states. Mimeographed copy, c. October 1953 (Box-folder 38: 7)
  - Press release, suggesting 7 points to strengthen Mid-East ties. Mimeographed copy, c. October 1953 (Box-folder 38: 8)
  - Press conference, American Friends of the Middle East headquarters, New York City, Clipping, 2 October 1953. (Box-folder 38: 9)
  - Letter to the editor, Arizona Daily Star, Printed copy, 28 October 1953. (Box-folder 38: 10)
  - Speech, New York Young Republican Club, Schwartz Restaurant, New York City, Press release, c. November 1953. (Box-folder 38: 11)
  - Memorandum to the Secretary-General of the United Nations and accompanying press release, Mimeographed copy and typescript drafts, 30 November 1953. (Box-folder 38: 12)
  - "Big Shoes - Little Men," Series of six articles for a column also entitled "Dear Abdullah." Typescript copies, 1954. (Box-folder 38: 13)
  - "Cairo Revisited," Carbon copy, 1954. (Box-folder 38: 14)
  - "The King and I," Carbon copy, 1954. (Box-folder 38: 15)
  - "Stranded in Gaza," Carbon copy, 1954. (Box-folder 38: 16)
  - "Jews of the Arab States and Israel," Council News, Printed copy, January 1954. (Box-folder 152: 50)
  - "Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, British Empire Club, Providence, Rhode Island. Clipping, 15 January 1954. (Box-folder 38: 17)
  - "Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, City Auditorium, Colorado Springs, Colorado. Clipping and subsequent letter to the editor, 9 February 1954, commenting on that review of his talk, 29 January 1954. (Box-folder 38: 18)
  - "The Inscrutable Smile on the Sphinx," American Mercury, Carbon copy, February 1954. (Box-folder 38: 19)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Carbon copy, 2 February 1954 (Box-folder 38: 20)
  - Interview, Denver Post, Printed copy, 7 February 1954. (Box-folder 38: 21)
  - "The Road to Middle East Peace," Speech, Hoover Library, Stanford, California. Clipping, 17 February 1954. (Box-folder 38: 22)
  - "Peace in the Holy Land," The Sign, Printed copy, July 1954. (Box-folder 38: 23)
  - Press conference, Cairo Press Syndicate, Cairo, Egypt, Press release, 5 August 1954. (Box-folder 38: 24)
  - "Justice before Peace for the Middle East," Human Events, Printed copy, 25 August 1954. (Box-folder 38: 25)
  - Interview of King Saud, 9 September 1954. Clippings and printed account in My King and Country, issued by the Saudi Arabian Legation in New Delhi (Box-folder 38: 26)
  - Press release, Typescript, October 1954. (Box-folder 38: 27)
  - Speech on Senator Estes Kefauver, Rotary Club, Cairo, Press release, 12 October 1954. (Box-folder 38: 28)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Printed copy, 23 December 1954. (Box-folder 38: 29)
  - Remarks, radio program Answers for Americans: "What's Ahead for the Middle East?" New York City, Typescript copy of panel discussion with Devin Garrity, Charles Hodges, and George Hamilton Combs, 26 December 1954. (Box-folder 38: 30)
  - "Smears and Fears," 1955. Series of short essays with the following headings: Slanted Liberal Press (Atlantic Magazine); NBC; Radio; Overseas Press Club; 1955 Tour; Harvard Invaded; Libraries; Review of What Price Israel? in the New York Times. Typescript (Box-folder 38: 31)
  - Speech, Hamilton College, Clinton, New York, Correspondence with Richard Muniz, c. January 1955. (Box-folder 38: 32)
  - "Which Way the Middle East?" Speech, Knife and Fork Club, Oshkosh, Wisconsin. Clipping and account by the club's secretary-treasurer, 11 January 1955. (Box-folder 38: 33)
  - "What's ahead for the Middle East?" Speech, American Friends of the Middle East, American Middle East Policy, and Federation of Syrian and Lebanese-American Clubs, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Clipping, 12 January 1955. (Box-folder 38: 34)
  - "Report of a Jewish Visitor to Arab Lands," Speech, Chicago Council for Foreign Relations, Chicago, Illinois. Clipping, 14 January 1955. (Box-folder 38: 35)
  - Press release, Carbon copy, 25 January 1955. (Box-folder 38: 36)
  - "The New Egypt," Speech, Louis W. and Maud Hill Center of Area Studies, St. Paul, Minnesota (broadcast over KUOM). Press release and correspondence, 22 February 1955. (Box-folder 38: 37)
  - Letter to the editor, Minneapolis Morning Tribune, Carbon copy, 1 March 1955. (Box-folder 38: 38)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald Tribune, (date written). Carbon copy, 8 March 1955 (Box-folder 38: 39)
  - Letter to the editor, Life, (date written). Carbon copy, 13 March 1955 (Box-folder 38: 40)
  - Debate with Harry Torczyner, radio program The State of the Nation: "Should the Arab States Receive Arms from the United States?" Facts Forum, Mutual Broadcasting System, New York City, Typescript, 17 March 1955. (Box-folder 38: 41)